spigotmc.org 2019-12-15

# SpigotMC Privacy Policy | SpigotMC - High Performance Minecraft

Want a better Minecraft server?   
Read about SpigotMC here!

  * SpigotMC Privacy Policy

Last Modified: August 24, 2019

* * *

**1\. Introduction**  
SpigotMC Pty. Ltd. (SpigotMC) is dedicated to protecting your personal information. This Privacy Policy applies to your use of any SpigotMC-owned websites, software, or associated services (collectively the “Platform”). Our Privacy Policy discloses our privacy practices and explains to you how we use, collect, store, transfer, and share your personal information. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may revise it from time to time without notice. If you do not agree with or accept our Privacy Policy in its entirety, you must not access or use the Platform.

**2\. Information Collected**  
Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed or otherwise anonymized.

Personal Information Collected Voluntarily Provided​

You will not be required to provide us with any personal information when you visit our Platform. However, portions of our Platform may require us to collect personal information about you. During your use of the Platform we may collect your name, email, address, telephone number, username, password, identifier, organization information, and other identifying details. Any personal information you submit via the Platform shall be used and disclosed in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We may also collect payment information that you make available to us for your use of the Platform. Please be aware that this payment information shall be stored by third party payment processors.

Personal Information Automatically Collected​

Whenever you use our Platform, we may collect non-identifying information from you, such as your IP address, interactions with the Platform, query information, location information, referring URL, browser, application interaction, mobile provider information, operating system, data usage, data transferred, and Internet Service Provider.

**3\. Anonymized Data**  
Please be aware that we me may collect and aggregate personal information from our Platform and may anonymize that information for our own research or internal purposes. Once such data has been anonymized, it cannot be traced back to you, the user.

**4\. Sharing and Use of Your Information**  
This section explains how SpigotMC may share or use your personal information. You consent to our use of your personal information for the following purposes:

    * CONTRACT ADMINISTRATION - We may use your personal information to negotiate, execute, renew and/or manage a contract with you.
    * ACCESS AND COMMUNICATIONS TO OUR PLATFORM AND SERVICES - We may use your personal information to (1) set-up and manage your SpigotMC account; (2) interact with you through our Platform (e.g. software updates, Platform announcements, etc.): and/or (3) manage and respond to your questions (e.g. technical, commercial or administrative) or requests for maintenance and support.
    * USE OF THE PLATFORM - We may use your personal information to (1) enable you to enjoy the use of, and easily navigate the Platform; and/or (2) better understand your needs and interests.
    * SHARING WITH THIRD PARTIES - We may use your personal information to share with other users of the Platform; to share with our partner companies or future affiliates for research, marketing, and other purposes. We may also share your information with service providers with whom we contract with such as contractors, web hosts, data providers and others so that we may provide you any services and allow you to access the Platform.
    * ALLOWING DOWNLOADS FROM THE PLATFORM - We may use your Personal Information to allow you to download data or content from the Platform.
    * TRAINING & IMPROVEMENTS - We may use your personal information to (1) train our employees or contractors to allow for a better Platform experience; and/or (2) improve the Platform.
    * DIRECT MARKETING AND INQUIRIES - We may use your personal information to contact you for additional products and services that you may be interested in or to respond to an inquiry.
    * LEGAL PROCESS - We may share your information: if we believe that disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation, legal or governmental request; to respond to a subpoena, court order, warrant, or other legal process; to enforce applicable Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy, including investigation of potential violations thereof; to protect the safety, rights, or property of the public, any person, or SpigotMC; to detect, prevent, or otherwise address security, technical issues, or illegal or suspected illegal activities (including fraud); or as evidence in litigation in which we are involved, as part of a judicial or regulatory proceeding.
  
**5\. Retention of Personal Information**  

    * SpigotMC will only retain your Personal Information for as long as required. We will keep your personal information:
    * For any legally required duration.
    * Until we no longer have a valid reason to keep or use your Personal Information. We retain the personal information we collect for so long as reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the information was collected, to perform our contractual and legal obligations, and for any applicable statute of limitations periods for the purposes of bringing and defending claims.
    * Until we receive a request to eliminate, delete, or modify any of your personal information stored with us.
  
**6\. Legal Basis for Processing Information**  

    * We process and use your personal information, where required by law, for the following purposes:
    * as necessary to fulfill this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Service;
    * consistent with your consent, which you can revoke at any time;
    * as necessary to comply with our legal obligations;
    * occasionally to protect your vital interests, or those of others;
    * as necessary in the public interest; and
    * as necessary for our (or others') legitimate interests, including our interests in providing a safe and profitable service to our users and partners.
  
**7\. Accessing and Editing Your Information**  
When using our Platform you may be able to access and edit some of your personal information via the Platform dashboard. If at any time, you have any questions or wish to review, change, or edit any additional personal information collected by us, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d5a1b8a5f8a6a0a5a5baa7a195a6a5bcb2baa1b8b6fbbaa7b2).

**8\. Removal of Information**  
If you wish to have any of your personal information stored within the SpigotMC Platform removed, please contact us using the information [here](https://www.spigotmc.org/threads/392153/). Please be aware that removal requests are not processed instantaneously. There may be a reasonable delay in removing any personal information requested.

You may make a removal request by following the instructions [here](https://www.spigotmc.org/threads/392153/). If you require additional details regarding the deletion or retention of your personal information, please contact us. All removal or deletion requests are subject to Section 6 and subject to any applicable laws. Additionally, we will retain and use your personal information (even after a removal or deletion request), where required, so that we may fulfill our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**9\. Cookies**  
We currently use cookies, please see our Cookie Policy.

**10\. Opting Out and Do Not Track**  
If you decide to provide us with your contact information, you agree that we may send you communications via text and email where you have consented. However, you may opt out of any communications and you may opt out of certain personal information submission where applicable. If you wish to opt out of certain communications or information collection, please do so via the Platform dashboard.

We currently do not offer website functionality for you to opt out of any “do not track” signals or listings.

**11\. Third Parties**  
SpigotMC may post links to third party websites on our Platform, which may include information that we have no control over. When accessing a third party site through our Platform, you acknowledge that you are aware that these third party websites are not screened for privacy or security issues by us. SpigotMC bears no responsibility for the information collected or used by any advertiser or third party website that you have visited through a link on our Platform. You must review that third party’s Terms of Service and Privacy Policy to understand how their information collection practices work.

**12\. Security Measures**  
We make reasonable attempts to protect your information by using physical and electronic safeguards in accordance with industry standards. However, as our Platform is hosted electronically we can make no guarantees as to the security or privacy of your information. For this reason, we recommend that you use anti-virus software, robust passwords, firewalls, and other precautions to protect yourself from security and privacy threats.

**13\. Your California Privacy Rights**  
SpigotMC permits residents of the State of California to use its Platform, and complies with the California Business and Professions Code §§ 22575-22579. If you are a California resident you may request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to any third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Various provisions throughout this Privacy Policy address requirements of the Californian privacy statutes. Although we do not disseminate your information to third parties without permission, you must presume that we collect electronic information from all visitors. You may contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#0c78617c217f797c7c637e784c7f7c656b6378616f22637e6b) with any questions regarding your California Privacy Rights.

**14\. Age Compliance**  
We intend to fully comply with American and international laws respecting children’s privacy. Therefore, we do not collect or process any information for any persons under the age of 13. If you are under 13 you may not access the Platform.

**15\. Transfer of Your Information Internationally**  
Please be aware that your personal information shall be transferred and processed in the United States and/or Australia. If you are an European Economic Community (EEC) citizen or resident, please be aware that your information may be transferred outside of the EEC. These data transfers are necessary to provide the Platform to you. Where we transfer your Personal Information outside of the EEC we may utilize standard contract clauses, the Swiss-US Privacy Shield, and other data protection mechanisms.

**16\. Merger and Acquisition**  
In the event that SpigotMC is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your personal information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. Please be aware that once the information is transferred your privacy rights may change.

**17\. Amendments**  
Like our Terms of Service, we may amend this Privacy Policy at any time without notice. When we amend this Privacy Policy, we will modify the date listed on this Agreement or we may contact you. You must agree to the amendments as a condition of your continued use of our Platform. If you do not agree, you must immediately cease using our Platform and notify us of your refusal to agree by e-mailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#0d79607d207e787d7d627f794d7e7d646a6279606e23627f6a).

**18\. Contacting Us**  
If you have any additional questions, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#01756c712c727471716e737541727168666e756c622f6e7366)

SpigotMC Cookie Policy

Last Modified: August 1, 2018

* * *

Spigot MC Pty. Ltd. (SpigotMC) is committed to protecting your personal information and ensuring your experience with us is as safe and as enjoyable as possible. The SpigotMC Cookie Policy should be read in conjunction with our Privacy Policy. Our Cookie Policy explains how and why we use “cookies” within our websites, software, or other associated services (collectively the “Platform”).

**What Are Cookies?**  
Cookies are small amounts of information in the form of text files sent by websites to computers, mobile phones or other devices when you visit a website. They allow companies to do various things, such as: tailoring content, personalizing website visits, and ensuring the security of any online experience. Cookies typically contain the name of the domain from which the cookie has come, the “lifetime” of the cookie, and a randomly generated unique number or other value. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies may come in different formats. Session cookies are temporary cookies that remain in your browser until you leave a website. Persistent cookies remain in your browser for a longer period of time. Third party cookies are cookies that are loaded onto your browser by third parties. Third party cookies are usually a type of persistent cookie and are stored until you delete them or they expire based on the time period set in each cookie.

**Our Use of Cookies**  
We use both session cookies and persistent cookies. Please be aware that cookies may be used on our Platform whether or not you have created an account or submitted information to us. We use session and persistent cookies for the following reasons:

    * Authentication, Personalization And Security \- Cookies help us verify your account and device and determine when you are logged in, so we can make it easier for you to access our Platform and to provide the appropriate experiences and features. We also use cookies to help prevent fraudulent use of login credentials and for security purposes.  

    * Performance And Analytics \- Cookies help us analyze how the Platform is being accessed and used, and enables us to track performance of the Platform. For example, we use cookies to provide insights regarding our Platform’s performance, such as page views, conversion rates, device information, visitor IP addresses and referral sites.
  
**Third Party Cookies**  
When you visit our Platform, you may also receive cookies from third parties. The information collected by such third party cookies is governed by their privacy policies. We use third party cookies for the following reasons:  

    * To allow our business partners to perform analytics and collect information and serve you advertisements.
    * To share information with third parties to gain insights and marketing information based on how you use our Platform.
    * To provide to social networks to better understand how users interact through the internet.
  
**Lawful Basis for Cookies Used By SpigotMC**  
We use cookies to ensure that our Platform functions as intended and to provide you with any services that you may have requested. Additionally, we use cookies based on your consent, where required by law, as stated within the Privacy Policy.

**Opting Out of Cookies**  
The cookies we use are designed to optimize your experience using our Platform. If you do not wish to receive cookies, most online browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. Please note that if you choose to refuse cookies some portions of the Platform may not function properly. Generally, you may change your cookie settings within the “options” or “preferences” tab. For more information related to your cookie settings, please use the “Help” option located within your browser. Additionally, the following links may be helpful if you wish to opt out of any cookies:

    * [Cookie settings in Safari web](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH5042) and [iOS](https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT201265)
Alternatively, you may wish to visit [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/), which contains comprehensive information regarding the management of cookies on your browser.

**Opting Out of Third Party Cookies**  
If you wish to limit third party advertising cookies, you may be able to turn cookies off by visiting the following links:

Opting out of any internet based advertising will only work for the browser you are currently using. Any additional browsers or devices with which you access our Platform must be opted out of separately. Some opt outs may only work if your browser accepts cookies. If you delete cookies, change your browser settings, switch browsers or computers, or use another device you may be required to opt out again.  

  * Loading...
  * Loading...
